Do you know the difference between
Holland and the Netherlands? Most people
think it's just two names for the same
country, but it's not. And why are the
people from this country called Dutch as
many confused them with people from
Denmark? Let's figure it out. Firstly,
the Netherlands is the official and only
correct name of the country. It got its
name from the words lowlands because a
significant part of its territory lies
below sea level. It's estimated that
about 60% of the country would be
underwater without the dikes, pumps, and
unique engineering systems in which the
Netherlands leads the world. The country
itself is made up of 12 provinces, and
Holland is just two of them, North
Holland, and South Holland. It's the
most developed region, home to famous
cities like Amsterdam, Roderdam, and the
Hague. In the past, it was a single
province called Holland, which became
the center of trade, seafaring, and
colonial expansion. Its ships and
merchants represented the nation around
the world. That's why foreigners began
to think the entire country was called
Holland and its people Hollanders. But
who are the Dutch? You see, back in the
days of the Holy Roman Empire, people
from these lands who spoke languages of
the Germanic family were called Deutsch,
which meant the language of the common
people as the elite were thought to
speak Latin. Over time, as European
nations began to form, this old word
changed in English to Dutch, and it
became associated specifically with the
Netherlands.